Partial Inventory of the Educational Research Council of America records
Hoover Institution Archives
Educational Research Council of America records
1951-1982
81094
Educational Research Council of America.
186 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 5 linear feet, 41 motion picture film reels. (84.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, minutes, reports, memoranda, studies, financial records, textbooks, teachers' manuals, printed matter, motion picture film, and other instructional materials, relating to elementary and secondary school education in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is stored off-site. It may be possible to have a limited number of boxes brought to the archives reading room for examination. A minimum of two days notice is required. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Educational research organization.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, minutes, reports, memoranda, studies, financial records, textbooks, teachers' manuals, printed matter, motion picture film, and other instructional materials, relating to elementary and secondary school education in the United States.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Education--United States.; Motion pictures.
Collection Contents
- Motion picture films (Film shelf Film shelf)
  For information on getting a use copy of motion picture films, please contact the Hoover Institution Archives
  - Reel 1, "The Set Of Quotients" Print 16-8, 250 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 2, "The Missing Factor Problem" Print 16-10, 250 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 3, "How Much is Blue," 100 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 4, "Roots of Geometry" Print No. 2, 650 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 5, PRT-20 4089, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 6, PRT-19 4595, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 7, PRT-18, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 8, PRT-28 4032, 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 9, Print #27 4138, 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 10, "The Integers," PRT-21 4644, 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 11, "Properties of Operations on Whole Numbers Educational Research Council Of America" 4032 Print #26, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 12, "Multi and Division" Print #25 4595, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 13, "The Whole Number" Print #21 4624, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 14, "Operations on Integers" PRT#24 4089, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 15, PRT-4 4038, 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 16, PRT-19 4138, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 17, PRT#20 4624, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 18, PRT#23 4830, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 19, PRT#19 3896, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 20, PRT#20 4644, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 21, PRT#25 4830, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 22, PRT-14 3903, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 23, PRT-15 3896, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 24, PRT-19 4038, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 25, "Rational Numbers" PRT-21 3850, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 26, "The Algorisms of Multiplication and Division" PRT-24 4269, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 27, "Numeration Systems" PRT-21 3857, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 28, "Properties of Operations Combined" PRT-26 4514, 800 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 29, "Sets and Numbers" "Educational Research Council Of America" PRT-24 4706, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 30, "The Need for Modern Mathematics" SRA #1, 700 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 31, #2, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 32, "#3 Addition of Whole Numbers, Lesson #2" SRA series, 600 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 33, "#3 Addition of Whole Numbers", SRA 950 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 34, "Multiplications and Divisions" Print #27, 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 35, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 36, 1000 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 37, PRT-20 3857, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 38, PRT-20 3850, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 39, PRT-20 3903, 1100 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 40, #4, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
  - Reel 41, ERC film #1, Print #7, 900 ft., 16mm film (Film shelf Film shelf)
- Rest of collection not yet described